<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Meet The Profiteer | War Is Business]]></title>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/categories/meet-the-profiteer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T18:21:15+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Corey Pein]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[One Of 'The Worst' War Profiteers Keeps Getting US Military Contracts]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/29/harry-sargeant-iot/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-29T16:24:57+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/29/harry-sargeant-iot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/03/harry-sargeant-iotc.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/03/harry-sargeant-iotc-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>Harry Sargeant III must be a pretty smart guy. After all, he&rsquo;s not in jail.</p>

<p>And isn&rsquo;t that what happens to most people when <a href="http://www.sfreporter.com/santafe/blog-2530-sheriff-solano-resigns_admits-wrongdoing.html">they</a> <a href="http://www.longislandpress.com/2010/10/01/mastic-man-charged-with-welfare-fraud-identity-theft">get caught</a> <a href="http://www.burlingtonfreepress.com/article/20110304/NEWS02/110304009/Vermont-woman-Gambling-led-me-to-embezzle-490-000">blatantly</a> <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/yblog_thelookout/20110328/us_yblog_thelookout/what-does-a-tax-cheat-look-like">ripping off the government</a>?</p>

<p>It isn&rsquo;t what happened to Sargeant. Ergo, the man is a genius.</p>

<p>Today, the politically connected businessman lives in reclusive luxury in Boca Raton, Florida, thanks in part to the tens of millions of dollars he allegedly personally received from an ill-gotten US military supply contract.</p>

<p>Earlier this month, freelance reporter Penn Bullock and Washington Post writer Kimberly Kindy wrote the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/pentagon-overpaid-oilman-millions-audit-finds/2011/03/17/ABQ6VFn_story.html">latest chapter</a> in Sargeant&rsquo;s story. It is a story of egregious misconduct and impunity by a member of the political-military-business elite—a story that may help future historians seeking to understand the advanced rot in the democratic foundations of 21st Century America.</p>

<p>The story opens in 2004, when Sargeant&rsquo;s company, <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/iotc/">IOTC</a>, won a huge wartime fuel-supply contract for US forces in Iraq. Since then, the government has overpaid Sargeant&rsquo;s company by $200 million, according to a new Pentagon audit report.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The audit is classified, but its findings were revealed by Bullock and Kindy <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/pentagon-overpaid-oilman-millions-audit-finds/2011/03/17/ABQ6VFn_story.html">in the Post</a>; its conclusions confirmed the findings of an earlier Congressional investigation.</p>

<h3>Partners first, enemies later</h3>

<p>Back in 2008, an IOTC competitor based in the UAE, Surpeme Fuels, filed a lawsuit that outlines the basic elements of Sargeant&rsquo;s scheme.</p>

<p>The lawsuit alleged that Sargeant&rsquo;s partner in the oil shipping business bribed officials in Jordan to obtain an exclusive license to transport fuel through the country. By obtaining preferential treatment from powerful people in Jordan, Sargeant effectively forced the Pentagon to hire his company, IOTC, to deliver fuel to Iraq.</p>

<p>And because Jordan had granted IOTC an exclusive license, the Pentagon had little choice but to pay Sargeant&rsquo;s inflated prices.</p>

<p>Like many grand moneymaking schemes, this one would blow up in Sargeant&rsquo;s face. It wasn&rsquo;t just that reporters and Congressional investigators had gotten wind of IOTC&rsquo;s price-gouging. The guy who had actually paid off the Jordanian officials <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&amp;sid=au._xkmde44I">turned around and sued Sargeant</a>.</p>

<p>The disgruntled money-man—who happens to be the brother-in-law of Jordan&rsquo;s King Abdullah—claimed that after he went through all the trouble of paying off the Jordanians to secure that exclusive transport license, Sargeant and IOTC&rsquo;s other one-third partner tried to cut him out of the profits.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2011/03/dark-knight-bank-robber-clowns-300x253.jpg" alt="" />Remember that scene in <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/">The Dark Knight</a> where The Joker&rsquo;s gang is robbing a bank and, one after another, the gang members keep shooting their comrades in the back so they don&rsquo;t have to share the loot? That&rsquo;s basically what Sargeant was accused of doing.</p>

<h3>Doubts about documents</h3>

<p>The 2008 Congressional investigation, led by US Rep. Henry Waxman (D-CA), accused Sargeant of &ldquo;the worst kind of war profiteering.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Last year, in a separate Congressional investigation into yet another corrupt fuel supply contract—the one for US forces in Afghanistan, which W.I.B. has <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/1655/news/is-the-pentagon-the-worlds-biggest-sucker/">covered previously</a>—Sargeant&rsquo;s company once again fell under suspicion. The Congressional report suggested that IOTC supplied Defense Logistics Agency officials with a document of dubious authenticity in hopes of winning the Afghanistan fuel supply contract.</p>

<p>This little detail, amounting to a fresh allegation against IOTC, has gone previously unreported. That is in keeping with the lackadaisical mainstream press treatment of the IOTC scandal, and war profiteering in general.</p>

<p>Although his case never generated the kind of massive headlines and widespread public outrage reserved for the likes of Charlie Sheen the steady pileup of negative publicity led Sargeant to withdraw from public life.</p>

<p>Following the Waxman investigation, Sargeant was forced to resign as finance chairman of the Florida Republican Party. Then the feds indicted an employee of Sargeant&rsquo;s for steering illegal campaign contributions to Gov. Charlie Crist.</p>

<p>Sargeant&rsquo;s attorney, Ron Uscher, has tried to cast his client as a victim:</p>

<blockquote><p>“A guy like Harry Sargeant has a lot of targets on his chest,” Uscher said. “He’s a rich guy, an oil guy, and he is bidding on war contracts.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Yet Sargeant evidently still has some influential friends. Last year, Florida State University named him an honored alumnus of its <a href="http://business.fsu.edu/press/sargeant.cfm">business school</a>. For innovations in the field of highway robbery?</p>

<h3>New contracts, despite bribery allegations</h3>

<p>Even since Sargeant&rsquo;s name became mud, his West Palm beach aviation company has won new contracts with the Defense Department.</p>

<p>The oil contract remains Sargeant&rsquo;s sweetest military deal, but his company <a href="http://www.palmbeachaviation.com/">Palm Beach Aviation</a> has won five Defense Department contracts since 2009-that&rsquo;s <em>after</em> the profiteering scandal-worth at least $120,000.</p>

<p>Three of those contacts originated with the US Special Operations Command. The descriptions of work are vague. One is &ldquo;flight time,&rdquo; another is &ldquo;air support.&rdquo; But the third contract specifies &ldquo;4th POG Airborne Operations.&rdquo;</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s a reference to the 4th Psychological Operations Group out of Fort Bragg, NC. It&rsquo;s a pretty secretive outfit that&rsquo;s involved with everything from interrogations to propaganda broadcasts and leaflets. The 4th POG was <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/s/yblog_upshot/20101001/us_yblog_upshot/army-embeds-active-duty-psyops-soldiers-at-local-tv-stations">in the news</a> recently for posting &ldquo;interns&rdquo; in civilian US newsrooms. The contract summaries do not make clear unclear exactly what the psyops group needs with Sargeant&rsquo;s aircraft.</p>

<p>Like the veiled allegation against IOTC in Congressional report on Manas Transit Center fuel contracts, the recent contracts awarded to Sargeant&rsquo;s other company have also gone unreported, until now.</p>

<p>The new contracts highlight the strangest thing about Sargeant&rsquo;s story. Although evidence continues to pile up in civil courtrooms that Sargeant&rsquo;s company bribed its way into a billion-dollar logistics contract and proceeded to soak American taxpayers for $200 million, the US military has kept shoveling money his way.</p>

<p>Why?</p>

<h3>Findings of Rep. Waxman&rsquo;s 2008 investigation:</h3>

<p>[gview file=&ldquo;/images/2011/03/iotc-waxman-letter.pdf&rdquo; width=&ldquo;100%&rdquo; height=&ldquo;350px&rdquo;]</p>

<h3>Lawsuit against IOTC by former business partner:</h3>

<p>[gview file=&ldquo;/images/2011/03/iotc-supreme-fuels.pdf&rdquo; width=&ldquo;100%&rdquo; height=&ldquo;350px&rdquo;]</p>

<h3>Relevant section of &ldquo;Mystery At Manas&rdquo; report:</h3>

<blockquote><p>Following the amendment to the contract, the Joint Stock Company sent a third letter to DLA- Energy thanking the agency for the solicitation amendment and reiterating that it must pre- approve all offerors to the agency’s tender. The Joint Stock Company’s letter attached a single memorandum of authorization for operations at Manas – for Mina Corporation (Red Star). Two of the other three offerors, AvCard and AeroControl, were not able to obtain authorization letters from the Joint Stock Company.    <strong>International Oil Trading Company (IOTC) did provide a commitment letter, but an official at DLA-Energy questioned the authenticity of the letter “because it looks substantially different than the Mina (Red Star) letter&hellip;. We believe that Red Star’s letter is authentic.”</strong></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[California Titanium Supplier Admits To Defrauding US Air Force]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/01/13/western-titanium-daniel-schroeder/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-13T11:14:21+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/01/13/western-titanium-daniel-schroeder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/01/western-titanium-inc.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/01/western-titanium-inc-150x150.jpg" alt="" /></a>Here is a case that demonstrates the US government&rsquo;s impotent response to war profiteering, even when it has proof, and even when private greed endangers the lives of troops.</p>

<p>What began several years ago as a serious federal fraud prosecution that had four corporate executives facing a combined 160 years in prison ended yesterday with the executives getting off almost scot-free—despite an admission of guilt in the case.</p>

<p>The companies involved—<a href="http://www.westerntitanium.com/quality.html">Western Titanium, Inc.</a> and its subsidiary, Mach 2 Metals, Inc.—pleaded guilty to mail fraud for selling falsely certified, substandard titanium for use in US military aircraft, including the C-17 transport aircraft; the F-15, F-22 and Joint Strike Fighters; and NASA&rsquo;s <a href="http://kepler.nasa.gov/">Kepler</a> spacecraft. According to the government&rsquo;s January 2007 indictment, &ldquo;engine mounts produced from the substandard and non-conforming titanium…were installed on two separate F-15 aircraft in active use by the United States Air Force.&rdquo;</p>

<p>These corporate <del>scapegoats</del> &ldquo;persons&rdquo; will pay a modest amount of restitution, and serve a period of probation, under the plea agreement with prosecutors in San Diego, California.</p>

<p>What of the actual, flesh-and-blood executives? These fortunate gentlemen will have the charges against them dismissed, so long as they promise not to run the same scam again.<!-- more --></p>

<p><a href="/images/2011/01/dan-shroeder-western-titanium.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/01/dan-shroeder-western-titanium.jpg" alt="" /></a>Here&rsquo;s a link to the December 2008 news release announcing the indictment of Western Titanium president and owner, Daniel Schroeder (pictured), along with sales executives Brian Misak and John Cotner, and &ldquo;quality assurance&rdquo; manager Cheem Ang (<a href="http://www.justice.gov/usao/cas/press/cas81208-WT.pdf">pdf</a>).</p>

<p>Initially, the four defendants were originally charged with eight counts of &ldquo;Fraud Involving Aircraft or Space Craft Parts,&rdquo; a crime that carries a maximum penalty of 20 years imprisonment and a $1 million fine.</p>

<p>Now, here&rsquo;s the full text of yesterday&rsquo;s press release announcing the resolution of the case. &ldquo;There will be no guilty plea or plea bargain. No way. Not Western or Dan Schroeder,” a corporate defense attorney <a href="http://www.macon.com/2009/01/23/596751/company-denies-allegations-of.html">told</a> a Georgia newspaper last year. She was bluffing, as it turns out, but that doesn&rsquo;t matter—what attorney wouldn&rsquo;t be happy with a deal like this?</p>

<blockquote><p>NEWS RELEASE SUMMARY &ndash; January 12, 2011</p></blockquote>

<p>United States Attorney Laura E. Duffy announced that defense contractors Western Titanium, Inc., and Mach 2 Metals, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Western Titanium) pled guilty today in federal court to committing mail fraud by falsely certifying that titanium they sold complied with certain military specifications.</p>

<p>According to court records and the defendants’ admissions at today’s hearing, Western Titanium reduced titanium ingot by having it forged into a large block of titanium. They then sold this material as forged bar. In doing so, employees of both defendants falsely certified to customers that the titanium met the requirements of AMS 4928, when in fact it did not. <strong>The defendants admitted that the loss caused by this offense was $51,350</strong>.</p>

<p>As part of today’s plea, the government also entered into deferred prosecution agreements with Daniel Schroder (Chief Executive Officer of Western Titanium), John Cotner (V.P of Sales, Western Titanium), Brian Misak (V.P of Sales, Western Titanium) and Cheem Ang (Quality Assurance Manager, Western Titanium). These agreements resulted in the <strong>dismissal of charges</strong> without prejudice against them <strong>on the condition that they not improperly sell titanium or titanium alloy certified to military or aerospace specifications</strong>.</p>

<p>A sentencing hearing is scheduled for April 29, 2011 at 9:00 a.m., before Judge Janis L. Sammartino.</p>

<p>Criminal Case No. 08-CR-4229-JLS</p>

<p>DEFENDANTS
Western Titanium, Inc.
Mach 2 [Metals]</p>

<p>SUMMARY OF CHARGES</p>

<p>Title 18, United States Code, Section 1341 and 2 &ndash; Mail Fraud. Maximum sentence: $500,000 or twice the gross gain/loss caused by the offense, $400 special assessment, a term of probation of 5 years and mandatory restitution of $51,350</p>

<p>[rssless][visitor]</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/diy/map">WHICH COMPANIES IN YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD PROFIT FROM WAR?<br/>
JOIN THE INVESTIGATION.<br/>
GAIN FULL ACCESS.</a></strong></p>

<p>[/visitor][/rssless]According to a November 2010 item in this metals trade journal, &ldquo;Schroeder &lsquo;apparently suffered a severe mental breakdown&rsquo;&rdquo; before the holidays last year.</p>

<p>How quickly things change. In a holiday 2008 real estate porn piece in its home-and-gardens section, the San Diego Union-Tribune featured Schroeder&rsquo;s 4,775-square foot mansion in La Jolla, California (<a href="http://www.domusstudio.com/10.30.08-SDHome-1.pdf">pdf</a>). Evidently, Schroeder had run into some trouble with &ldquo;neighborhood skeptics&rdquo; and permitting agencies, concerned about the gaudy structure&rsquo;s impact on the environment, and &ldquo;the potential for Indian artifacts and burial sites on the property,&rdquo; which the U-T describes as a &ldquo;magical&rdquo; site near the beach.</p>

<p>Inside, the home is appointed with &ldquo;a linear fireplace from Canada…a radiant heat system in the floor… The master bath includes a shower/steam room with a view to the ocean&rdquo; and a &ldquo;compact spa tub"… "The floor is paved…in fossilized sandstone…&rdquo; The kitchen boasts a &ldquo;four-burner Wolf stove, two Sub-Zero refigreator freezers, two Dacor convection ovens… Just beyond the countertop is a 130-bottle wine rack… the Schroeders prefer reds.&rdquo; In the relatively modest living room, they have a &ldquo;60-inch Aquos flat-screen TV.&rdquo; Shroeder has another flat-screen in his &ldquo;man cave"—a converted "three-car detached garage, complete with heated floor, grease pit…satellite radio [and] car and motorcycle collection.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Here is a picture of the master bedroom. Yet another TV hidden in the foot of the bed &ldquo;rises into view at the touch of a button.&rdquo;
<a href="/images/2011/01/dan-lisa-schroeder-san-diego-bedroom.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/01/dan-lisa-schroeder-san-diego-bedroom-300x239.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The Schroeders did not want to reveal the cost of the home, but they did admit that they went over budget…</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;&lsquo;We kind of sucked it up,&rsquo; [Shroeder&rsquo;s wife] Lisa said.</p>

<p>According to the U-T, the roof on the home is made of a titanium alloy. We can only assume that it was fully tested and certified.</p>

<p><em>h/t to W.I.B. contributor <a href="http://maassive.com">Dave Maass</a> in San Diego.</em></p>

<p><em>Documents: Western Titanium February 2009 <a href="/images/2011/01/mach_indictment.pdf">grand jury indictment</a>; December 2008 <a href="http://docs.google.com/viewer?a=v&amp;q=cache:UtR5Fio1nfMJ:www.justice.gov/usao/cas/press/cas81208-WT.pdf+Western+Titanium+Daniel+Schroeder+2008&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=uk&amp;pid=bl&amp;srcid=ADGEESj6osctmt2Cpvx-dWJUMuc7trNpjmpyvocVR5PaAblv1ex-DNXZC4dqMJh_o7CdDuSWUhbm8HQvh587riP4zLynnJBuTbCQkO2NKvxEQMexQDnv3WyVlgimi9yn5Oh_jOegs7zV&amp;sig=AHIEtbS30EEnywDiG3_l4LkJ2SoQCEdnag">press release</a>, US Attorney Karen P. Hewitt&rsquo;s office</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Security Clearances Are Meaningless: Classified Program Manger Embezzled $7k/Mo. For Three Years]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/12/04/security-clearances-are-meaningless-classified-program-manger-embezzled-7kmo-for-three-years/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-04T15:58:27+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/12/04/security-clearances-are-meaningless-classified-program-manger-embezzled-7kmo-for-three-years</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2010/12/Raytheon.gif" alt="" />Federal prosecutors in California busted a manager at Raytheon, the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/top-150-warcorps/">fifth-largest</a> US military contractor, for embezzling over a quarter-million dollars in a three-year period.</p>

<p>The manager, David L. Culbertson, plead guilty to fraud earlier this week, and agreed to reimburse Raytheon the $265,000 he stole from the company, and thus the taxpayers. It&rsquo;s unclear whether his sentence, to be set in February, will include jail time. One might think that the breach of public trust would demand a harsher sentence, but that&rsquo;s not always how these cases out. In my experience covering crime and courts in America, it&rsquo;s not unusual for judges to give a slap on the wrist to members of the police and military establishment, including civilian contractors.</p>

<p>Certainly, it won&rsquo;t be a surprise to hear Culbertson&rsquo;s attorneys argue that his years of work &ldquo;protecting the nation&rdquo; in some way mitigates his offense, when in fact, the opposite is true.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>[visitor]</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/diy/wib/?compname=Raytheon&amp;compplace=United%20States">HELP RESEARCH RAYTHEON. ACCESS MORE OF THIS SITE. BANISH THESE BANNERS.</a></strong></p>

<p>[/visitor]I feel the same way about Greg Solano, who was, until very recently, the relatively forward-thinking county sheriff of Santa Fe, New Mexico, where I lived for the past two years. I liked Solano, and cheered on his <a href="http://www.sfreporter.com/santafe/article-5599-anthonys-empire.html">campaign</a> against local public corruption. So much for all that. Last week, Solano resigned after <a href="http://www.sfreporter.com/santafe/blog-2530-sheriff-solano-resigns_admits-wrongdoing.html">admitting</a> to selling stolen, out-of-warranty body armor to military servicemembers—<a href="http://www.sfreporter.com/santafe/article-5787-zanes-world.html">profiteering on a petty scale</a>, made more despicable by the fundamental hypocrisy it reveals. He, too, deserves a harsher punishment than a run-of-the-mill fraudster.</p>

<p>Culbertson&rsquo;s scheme, which involved duplicate expense reimbursements, was as simple—and as stupid—as Solano&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>Culbertson was a &ldquo;security manager&rdquo; who &ldquo;worked on a number of classified programs." Raytheon&rsquo;s failure to detect such crude malfeasance by a high-level employee doesn&rsquo;t inspire confidence in the company&rsquo;s lucrative new &rdquo;<a href="http://www.raytheon.com/capabilities/products/cybersecurity/">cyber security</a>&ldquo; ventures, which it is now peddling to governments <a href="http://www.arabianbusiness.com/raytheon-makes-play-for-gulf-cybersecurity-deals-361018.html">around the world</a>.</p>

<p>More details of Culbertson&rsquo;s case are in the following press release, sent out by the US Attorney&rsquo;s office for the central district of California on November 30.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>FORMER RAYTHEON EMPLOYEE PLEADS GUILTY TO EMBEZZLING NEARLY $265,000 THROUGH CLASSIFIED CELL PHONE PROGRAM</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>LOS ANGELES – A Fullerton man has pleaded guilty to federal fraud charges, admitting that he stole several hundred thousands of dollars from a defense contractor in connection with a cell phone program he operated for employees working on classified programs.</p>

<p>David L. Culbertson, 55, pleaded guilty yesterday to one count of mail fraud and agreed to pay approximately $265,000 in restitution to the Raytheon Company.</p>

<p>A long-time security manager at Raytheon, Culbertson worked on a number of classified programs. In 1989, Culbertson began providing cell phones to certain Raytheon personnel who also worked on classified programs. In order to disassociate the cell phones from Raytheon, Culbertson had the bills associated with the cell phones sent to his residence, and he then paid the bills using personal funds. He then sought reimbursement from Raytheon, which passed on the costs of the cell phone program to the federal government.</p>

<p>In a plea agreement filed in United States District Court, Culbertson admitted that, beginning in 2003, he frequently sought multiple reimbursements from Raytheon for the same cell phone bills, essentially double- or triple-billing Raytheon and the federal government. Culbertson was able to carry out the scheme by showing the same original cell phone bills to different people in order to gain approval for his reimbursement requests.</p>

<p>For example, Culberton would take a set of phone bills to one individual in order to obtain a petty cash reimbursement, and then take these samephone bills to another individual in order to obtain a check reimbursement. Culbertson was able to avoid detection of his scheme by claiming to the various reimbursement approvers that they could not keep copies of the phone bills due to confidentiality concerns. Between 2003 and 2006, Culbertson embezzled approximately $265,000 through his fraudulent scheme.</p>

<p>Culberton’s scheme was ultimately detected through an internal audit in 2006, which prompted Raytheon to terminate Culbertson in early 2007. Raytheon has been fully cooperative with the federal government’s investigation and prosecution of this matter.</p>

<p>Culbertson pleaded guilty before United States District Stephen V. Wilson, who is scheduled to sentence the defendant on February 7. Culbertson faces a statutory maximum sentence of 20 years in federal prison, but Judge Wilson will make the final determination as to the appropriate sentence in the case.</p>

<p>The investigation into Culbertson was conducted by the National Reconnaissance Office &ndash; Office of Inspector General and the Defense Criminal Investigative Service.</p>

<p>[visitor]</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/diy/wib/?compname=Raytheon&amp;compplace=United%20States">HELP RESEARCH RAYTHEON. ACCESS MORE OF THIS SITE. BANISH THESE BANNERS.</a></strong></p>

<p>[/visitor]</p>

<hr />
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[60 Minutes On Viktor Bout]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/11/26/60-minutes-on-viktor-bout/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-26T15:31:57+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/11/26/60-minutes-on-viktor-bout</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somehow I missed this on Sunday. Maybe you did, too. Watch the <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/video/watch/?id=7076477n&amp;tag=mncol;lst;5">60 Minutes segment</a> on Viktor Bout before his trial commences in New York.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bout Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/11/16/bout-time/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-16T09:48:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2010/11/16/bout-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2010/11/viktor-bout-tv-jail.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote><p>Thailand extradited Viktor Bout to the U.S. to face terrorism charges, ending two
years of legal wrangling over the accused Russian arms dealer dubbed the “merchant of death.”</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2010-11-16/thailand-to-extradite-accused-russian-arms-dealer-viktor-bout-to-the-u-s-.html">Bloomberg</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2010-11-16/thailand-to-extradite-accused-russian-arms-dealer-viktor-bout-to-the-u-s-.html"></a><!-- more --></p>

<blockquote><p>Two motorcades — one apparently a decoy — made the trip to the airport and shortly afterward an airport official confirmed that he had left on a small chartered aircraft.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/11/17/world/asia/17thai.html">New York Times</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Bout, who speaks six languages and has used at least seven separate identities, faces a maximum sentence of life in prison if convicted in the United States on charges including conspiracy to kill US nationals and providing material support or resources to a foreign terrorist organisation.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5jOJm16_MMh3hBMCVCR4QxyQXkMgQ?docId=CNG.f786f35478d537ce7ea65301a98c7313.a61">AFP</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Moscow has been demanding his release, saying that Mr Bout is an innocent businessman and criticising Thai moves to extradite him as politically motivated… Analysts say Moscow is perhaps worried he might turn state witness on trial in the US, and reveal more than Russia would be comfortable with.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-pacific-11763221">BBC</a></p>

<p>The full backstory from <a href="http://www.spiegel.de/international/world/0,1518,721532,00.html">Der Spiegel</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
