<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: War Is Business Business | War Is Business]]></title>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/categories/war-is-business-business/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T18:21:15+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Corey Pein]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[W.I.B. On Air]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/04/13/w-i-b-on-air/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T11:03:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/04/13/w-i-b-on-air</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c6n5WyrKiyg"><img src="/images/2011/04/cp-on-aloyna-apr12-150x111.jpg" alt="" /></a>The Alyona Show had me on yesterday to talk about the US Defense Department&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.time.com/time/nation/article/0,8599,2064468,00.html">apparently untouchable</a> budget, the <a href="http://demilitarize.org/">Global Day of Action on Military Spending</a> and the <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/04/04/us-libya-arms-idUSTRE7331OO20110404">marketing opportunities</a> created by the war in Libya. You can watch the segment on the show&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c6n5WyrKiyg">YouTube channel</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[By Popular Demand: Full RSS Feeds]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/10/full-feeds/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-10T13:20:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/10/full-feeds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A number of readers have complained about the truncated RSS feeds for certain posts. As a publisher, my initial reaction is to say, &ldquo;well, tough.&rdquo; But as an RSS booster with hundreds of subscriptions in my own reader, I ultimately couldn&rsquo;t bear my own hypocrisy.</p>

<p>Praise be to God and rejoice: Full feeds are back, for all posts.</p>

<p>With the recent introduction of <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/category/news/aggregated/">aggregated</a> items, the tempo of this site has picked up. To keep the feed manageable, I&rsquo;ve tweaked some settings so readers can tell right away whether something is an original W.I.B. story or something we&rsquo;ve (gag) &ldquo;curated.&rdquo; Here&rsquo;s what to look for:<!-- more -->
<img src="/images/2011/03/new-rss-feeds-example.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I know that for some people, the steady flow of <del>sarcasm</del> W.I.B.-certified <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/tag/investment-advice">Investment Advice</a>—which ranges between 3 and 10 quickie posts a day—is too much of a good thing. If you&rsquo;d prefer to follow a less frequently updated feed, one that only shows W.I.B.&rsquo;s original work, <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/feed/?cat=-1609">subscribe using this link</a> instead.</p>

<p>Personally, I don&rsquo;t think 10 posts a day is too much for a news site that covers a beat as big as the global arms trade. Given the budget to hire enough reporters, I&rsquo;d have 100 items a day. Until then, a good deal of care goes into the selection of those aggregated items, which represent maybe 1/50th of the war-and-business-related news I follow. In other words, I sift through a lot of crap to find the rare stuff worth knowing about—and when I find something good, I pass it on.</p>

<p>For that reason I&rsquo;ll continue to recommend the full feed. <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/feed/">Subscribe here</a> if you&rsquo;re not already.</p>

<p>While we&rsquo;re on the subject: The truly hopeless, un-rehabbable news junkies out there should definitely follow <a href="twitter.com/warisbusiness">@warisbusiness</a> on Twitter. That feed contains all of our original stories, links to all the aggregated items, plus a lot more news we think is worth checking out, faster than it appears on the site.</p>

<p>Another favor to ask: It took some creative coding to get the full RSS feeds to play nice with the custom architecture of this site. If you notice any annoying bugs, don&rsquo;t hesitate to <a href="http://warisbusiness.com/contact">get in touch</a>.</p>

<p>Finally, if you&rsquo;re one of those RSS readers who never clicks through to the website—I know you&rsquo;re out there—consider <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;hosted_button_id=K7AVMBFDT96JA">making a donation</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Traffic, New Server]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/06/more-traffic-new-server/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-06T22:29:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/06/more-traffic-new-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rising traffic had been making a bloody mess of this site&rsquo;s performance. Good news, though: As of this weekend, W.I.B. has a new webhost, and things are running smoother.</p>

<p>The server upgrade will ensure that the site stays accessible, and leave a little room for growth. But it also means increased monthly overhead. Please help defray those expenses by making a small <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;hosted_button_id=K7AVMBFDT96JA">donation</a>. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Site Expansion: Profiles Of 3,100 Foreign Military Companies Working In Iraq And Afghanistan—Plus Maps]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/28/big-site-expansion-profiles-of-3100-foreign-military-companies-working-in-iraq-and-afghanistane28094plus-maps/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-28T20:16:10+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/28/big-site-expansion-profiles-of-3100-foreign-military-companies-working-in-iraq-and-afghanistane28094plus-maps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Regular readers may have noticed that this site has been a little light in the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/category/news/wib/">original reporting</a> category during the past couple of weeks. There are two reasons for this (and for an accidental burst of Twitter gibberish from <a href="http://twitter.com/warisbusiness">@warisbusiness</a>):</p>

<p><a href="/images/2011/02/g4s-marrakech.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/02/g4s-marrakech-300x131.jpg" alt="" /></a>One, I took a short vacation. (Of course, I couldn&rsquo;t leave W.I.B. totally behind, and between cups of mint tea and battles with a nasty food-borne illness, I noticed the logo of the international private security company, G4S, on a van parked at the main plaza in Marrakech. This may rank among the nerdiest tourist photos ever snapped, as well as the worst-composed.)</p>

<p>The second reason for the quiet time: I&rsquo;ve been wrapping up a major expansion of the site—one that not only makes W.I.B. more useful but also, I hope, points to a new model for internet-age investigative reporting.</p>

<p>This weekend I uploaded individual profiles for 3,100 US military contractors. These are much more attractive than the handful of old dossiers I&rsquo;d produced by hand. Each is complete with a map and, more importantly, is <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/g4s-plc/#logo">EDITABLE</a> by users.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I haven&rsquo;t designed a navigation tool for all these new pages yet—which means that, for now, the simplest way to peruse the company dossiers is through the search box in the upper right-hand corner of the site.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s also this <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/">mashup map</a> showing the locations of 50 of the largest contractors, each with reported annual revenue of over $4 billion.</p>

<p>Finally, you can browse through the dossiers <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/category/research/dossier/?orderby=title&amp;order=ASC">at this page</a>.  Here&rsquo;s the one for <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/g4s-plc/">G4S</a>, whose van I spotted in Marrakech.</p>

<h3>There are way more than 3,100 Pentagon contractors. How did these companies make the cut?</h3>

<p>I wanted to be somewhat more selective with this data set than with the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/diy/map/">last map</a> I built, which depicted a sizable hodgepodge of all Defense Department contracts signed in fiscal year 2010. Besides filtering out some of those more mundane military logistical deals, I also wanted to create something that could be expanded upon, and was easier to use than the clunky beta version of the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/diy/wib">DIY investigations</a> tool.</p>

<p>In short, I wanted to bring the site closer to my original vision of an interactive, constantly updated directory showing the companies and people who have profited, one way or another, from war.</p>

<p>So, to build this new database, I downloaded 11 years of US Defense Department spending data for contracts performed in Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, Yemen and Israel. (More countries will be added later.) Cleaning up the records, removing duplicates and otherwise wrangling a tangled mess of information into usable shape for a website took so long, and was so mind-numbing that I prefer not to discuss it further at the moment…</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s give about those dossiers a look, shall we? I&rsquo;ve anticipated some of your questions.</p>

<h3>Cool, but… why can&rsquo;t I see all the data?</h3>

<p>Actually, you can… if you take a minute to register, which can be done one of two ways:</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;hosted_button_id=K7AVMBFDT96JA">make a donation</a>, after which you should be redirected to a registration form.</p>

<p>Or you can contribute to W.I.B.&rsquo;s research, by looking up a missing fact and adding it to the database. That&rsquo;s why it says &ldquo;give info to get info"—because if you can&rsquo;t donate money to this investigative project, you can donate a few seconds of your time. Click one of the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/g4s-plc/#logo">EDIT</a> buttons to get started.</p>

<h3>I clicked the button, and all I see is an empty white box.</h3>

<p>W.I.B. is beginning to outgrow its server, which is a good problem to have, but nonetheless a source of annoyance.</p>

<p>Give the form a minute to load. Then, consider <a href="https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;hosted_button_id=K7AVMBFDT96JA">making a donation</a> to help W.I.B. move to a dedicated host. Know anyone with free space in a <a href="http://www.techreview.com/blog/mimssbits/26095/">hardened server-bunker</a> in a remote mountainside? Then <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/contact/">get in touch</a>.</p>

<h3>Why didn&rsquo;t you just make it a Wiki?</h3>

<p>Because this website isn&rsquo;t a Wiki, and I&rsquo;m not interested in publishing unverified information from anonymous users. You can maintain your anonymity while editing the profiles, and register under a pseudonym if you like—but each submission will be verified by at least one other live human being before it&rsquo;s posted to the site.</p>

<p>Granted, the original records, from the US Defense Department, do contain errors. But they merely serve as a starting point for what aims to be a much more complete public directory of arms traders and military contractors.</p>

<h3>Sounds good. Where should I start?</h3>

<p>Check <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/">this map</a> to see if there&rsquo;s a major war contractor near you. Or check out one of these company profiles, which I&rsquo;ve moved out from behind the registration wall:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/bae/">BAE</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/balfour-beatty/">BALFOUR BEATTY</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/blackwater/">BLACKWATER</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/blue-hackle-group/">BLUE HACKLE GROUP</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/dyncorp/">DYNCORP</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/eads/">EADS</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/general-dynamics/">GENERAL DYNAMICS</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/johnson-johnson/">JOHNSON &amp; JOHNSON</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/l-3/">L-3</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/lockheed/">LOCKHEED</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/mina-corp/">MINA CORP</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/northrop/">NORTHROP</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/raytheon/">RAYTHEON</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/united-technologies/">UNITED TECHNOLOGIES</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/unity-logistics/">UNITY LOGISTICS</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/urs-group/">URS GROUP</a> | <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/watan-group/">WATAN GROUP</a></p>

<p>Here are their locations on a map:
[mashup width=&ldquo;100%&rdquo; show=&ldquo;query&rdquo; show_query=&ldquo;post_type=profiles&amp; post__in=3739,3742,,3743,3744,3746,3747,3748,3749,3754,3755,3792,3958,3981,4107,4299,6360,6378&rdquo;]</p>

<p><a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/contact/">Let me know</a> what you think—especially if you run into any bugs while editing the entries.</p>

<p>(It wasn&rsquo;t hackers that produced this weekend&rsquo;s Twitter spam. It was a switch flicked the wrong way during the mass of profile uploads. This ranks right up there with the great RSS feed fiasco of…last month. Apologies to my followers.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are You Smarter Than A Hollywood Copywriter?]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/14/happy-valentines-day/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-14T11:30:48+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/14/happy-valentines-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/02/jessica-simpson-private-valentine.jpg" alt="" />
Expect a lighter posting schedule this week, with a couple of sure-to-be-excellent guest posts by WIB contributor <a href="http://maassive.com/">Dave Maass</a>. He promises not to review <a href="http://www.movieposterdb.com/posters/08_12/2008/1034320/l_1034320_1716ce0c.jpg">this</a> 2008 Jessica Simpson vehicle. (&ldquo;From A-List to En-List…&rdquo; God God.)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m skipping town to replenish my Vitamin D levels in an Arabic-speaking North African country (not <a href="http://www.google.co.uk/search?sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;q=egypt+kebab#hl=en&amp;q=egypt&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;tbo=u&amp;tbs=nws:1&amp;source=og&amp;sa=N&amp;tab=wn&amp;fp=d0979c1b17805313">that one</a>). The <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/tag/investment-advice">investment advice</a> feed is on auto-pilot. Consult your broker.</p>

<p>One more thing. It&rsquo;s a reminder.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This website is a project with <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/about-wib/">big ambitions</a>. One of those is to build a network of occasional correspondents from all over the world.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;d like to contribute to WIB, send me a note via the <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/contact/">contact page</a>. There&rsquo;s no need to send a complete résumé, but do let me know your location, availability, relevant skills (writing, photography, research, tech) and your interest in the site.</p>

<p>This morning&rsquo;s <a href="http://wartimecontracting.gov/">Wartime Contracting Commission</a> hearing in Washington, DC is an example the kind of thing I would&rsquo;ve liked to have covered with a live pair of eyes and ears. Alas. Maybe it&rsquo;ll be on <a href="http://www.c-spanvideo.org/congress">C-SPAN</a>?</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the official announcement, in case anybody wants to listen in and take notes.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Wartime Contracting Commission will take sworn testimony from contractors on Afghan construction</strong></p></blockquote>

<p>…The hearing will begin at 9:30 a.m. Monday, Feb. 14, in Room 216 of the Hart Senate Office Building, 2nd and C Streets, NE, Washington, DC. The hearing is open to the public and to news media…</p>

<p>Industry witnesses for the Feb. 14 session will be:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>William Van Dyke, President, Black &amp; Veatch Special Projects, which participated in construction of a $300 million power plant in Kabul, Afghanistan.</p></li>
<li><p>Michael E. McKelvy, President, Government, Environment &amp; Nuclear Division, CH2M Hill, whose work in Afghanistan has included military-base expansions.</p></li>
<li><p>Charles Mouzannar, Executive Vice President, AMEC Earth and Environmental, Inc., which is responsible for the Afghan Defense University in Kabul and the Afghan National Army garrison in Herat.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>… Projects include power plants, schools, hospitals and clinics, prisons, facilities for the Afghan National Army and Police, plus facilities for use by American and allied troops in the country.</p>

<p>Commission Co-Chairs <a href="http://www.wartimecontracting.gov/index.php/about/commissioners/thibault">Michael Thibault</a> [the Democratic appointee, who started working for Pentagon contractors after leaving a job as a contract auditor for the Pentagon] and <a href="http://www.wartimecontracting.gov/index.php/about/commissioners/shays">Christopher Shays</a> [the Republican appointee, a former Congressman and Peace Corps volunteer] said the hearing will include discussion of problems with planning, costs, delays, and host-nation sustainability of construction projects, but has other purposes as well.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Contractors have taken a lot of criticism for their performance in Iraq and Afghanistan, including from us,&rdquo; Thibault said. &ldquo;But they have also, in general, provided vital, quality support to our military and to American policy objectives in Afghanistan. We&rsquo;ll have some challenging questions about their performance, but we also want to hear from contractors how the government could do a better job of planning and managing contracts.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Co-Chair Shays said, &ldquo;After more than nine years of U.S. military, reconstruction, and development operations in Afghanistan, we are still seeing an alarming incidence of waste, fraud, and abuse. Some waste will always occur when you&rsquo;re operating in a remote, impoverished country with different cultural norms and an active insurgency. But some of the problems are due to bad planning, insufficient attention to competitive acquisition, and poor oversight-weaknesses that should have been corrected long ago. And just as alarming are projects that are done well but also become waste because they are not culturally sensitive or sustainable after our forces leave.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
