<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: News | War Is Business]]></title>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/categories/news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T21:25:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Corey Pein]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[State Lawmaker Accused Of Diverting Contract Money To GOP Candidates]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2012/04/08/state-lawmaker-accused-of-diverting-contract-money-to-gop-candidates/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T21:20:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2012/04/08/state-lawmaker-accused-of-diverting-contract-money-to-gop-candidates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2012/04/brian-boquist.jpg"><img src="/images/2012/04/brian-boquist-150x109.jpg" alt="" /></a>I came across an interesting story recently about Brian Boquist, a conservative Oregon legislator who also runs a hot-zone aviation business and a military training range, both of which operate on variations of the name ICI, or International Charter, Inc. One of Boquist&rsquo;s partners in ICI, a helicopter pilot, made some pretty <a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/blog-28192-oregon_lawmaker_accused_of_diverting_money_from_a_defense_contractor_to_bankroll_gop_candidates.html">startling allegations</a> in a lawsuit filed in January:</p>

<blockquote><p>The complaint was filed this Jan. 31 in U.S. District Court in Oregon by former ICI vice president and co-owner Danny O'Brien and his wife, Lorrie, who live in Lakewood, Wash. The lawsuit names Boquist; his wife, Peggy; and their business partner, Marcus Hines of Arizona, as defendants.</p></blockquote>

<p>The complaint says Boquist forced the O'Briens out of the firm, ICI Wyoming, at the end of last year, following a disagreement over the direction of the company.</p>

<p>After Boquist forced the O'Briens out, the complaint says, the company&rsquo;s bookkeeper resigned. The bookkeeper, lawsuit says, then provided the O'Briens with evidence that Boquist and his wife had been secretly diverting money from the firm to other projects, including a new company they had started in 2008 called Powder River Cartridge Company, LLC.</p>

<p>Through this new company, the complaint says, &ldquo;the Boquists directed thousands of dollars of revenue generated by ICI Wyoming to their own use and without [the O'Briens'] knowledge or consent, including but not limited to political campaign contributions for causes supported or advocated by Defendant Brian Boquist, in his capacity as an Oregon State Senator.&rdquo;</p>

<p>I followed up this news in <a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-18791-senator_of_fortune.html">another article for <em>WW</em></a>, which explained in greater detail how Boquist makes his money, but I never heard back from any of the plaintiffs. Nick R. Martin at Talking Points Memo also <a href="http://tpmmuckraker.talkingpointsmemo.com/2012/02/oregon_senator_stung_by_suit_over_combat_camp_cash.php">followed up</a>, but succeeded only in obtaining a cryptic comment from Boquist&rsquo;s wife.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA['A Parallel Quagmire: The Trans-Afghanistan Gas Pipeline]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2012/01/03/a-parallel-quagmire-the-trans-afghanistan-gas-pipeline/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-03T16:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2012/01/03/a-parallel-quagmire-the-trans-afghanistan-gas-pipeline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2012/01/tapi-ipi-pipelines-afghanistan-pakistan-india-iran-turkmenistan.gif"><img src="/images/2012/01/tapi-ipi-pipelines-afghanistan-pakistan-india-iran-turkmenistan-300x189.gif" alt="" /></a>The perpetually <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/12/21/world/asia/american-commander-in-afghanistan-john-allen-hints-at-post-2014-military-presence.html?_r=1&amp;pagewanted=all">postponed</a> U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan tracks a little too closely with timelines for another <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FUBAR">fubar</a> project, the Turkmenistan-Afghanistan-Pakistan-India gas pipeline.</p>

<p>TAPI, as the pipeline is known, ought to be called TBD. It&rsquo;s been a Big Oil dream since the mid-1990s, and a decade&rsquo;s-long American military presence in the region has brought it no closer to reality. The Afghan news outfit Killid Media <a href="http://tkg.af/english/reports/political/731-how-long-before-gas-in-pipeline?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+tkg_english+%28English%29">reported</a> yesterday that &ldquo;Little has happened on the TAPI natural gas project involving four countries a year after [an] agreement was signed by the governments.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>Planners are promising the project could be in operation by 2016. … Work which was delayed by security concerns will <strong>start from early 2012 and finish in two years</strong>…</p></blockquote>

<p>Are the pipeline planners scheduling based on the projected 2014 timeline for U.S. withdrawal from Afghanistan, or vice-versa? Does it matter? Either way, there are signs that the U.S. government is doubling down on the project as Pakistani leaders have indicated they might prefer a competing pipeline proposed to connect Pakistan and a U.S. adversary, Iran.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Pakistan&rsquo;s Express Tribune <a href="http://tribune.com.pk/story/308650/wielding-soft-power-us-offers-to-finance-tapi-gas-pipeline/">reports</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Addressing students of Lahore University of Management Sciences…US ambassador to Pakistan Cameron Munter had termed Pakistan-Iran gas pipeline deal unfeasible. A <strong>viable alternative</strong>, in his view, was the Turkmenistan-Afghanistan- Pakistan-India (TAPI) pipeline project via Afghanistan. …</p></blockquote>

<p>Sources inform The Express Tribune that the Export-Import Bank (EIB) of the United States as well as the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), an “independent” US agency, <strong>have offered Pakistan financing for TAPI</strong>.</p>

<p>The U.S. is also the key shareholder in the Asian Development Bank, another financing agency for TAPI, as W.I.B. <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/320/features/bullet-points/hillary-hawks-boeing-gear-to-india/">noted previously</a>.</p>

<p>But promises of more American dollars may ring hollow, as <a href="http://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:vCPMCIT2MsoJ:www.nation.com.pk/pakistan-news-newspaper-daily-english-online/Opinions/Editorials/17-Sep-2011/Lets-say-No-to-US+&amp;cd=5&amp;hl=en&amp;ct=clnk&amp;gl=us">the following letter</a> in a prominent English-language Pakistani newspaper about the competing pipeline projects suggests.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Pakistan,&rdquo; the letter begins, will &ldquo;not take any dictation from anyone.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>The gas pipeline project with Iran is a lifeline for us</strong> for overcoming the energy crisis. The US energy team…came up with a <strong>strange demand</strong> that Pakistan should abandon this project and instead offered assistance for the Turkmenistan-Afghanistan-Pakistan-India gas pipeline project (TAPI) as an alternative option. …</p></blockquote>

<p>Washington has already successfully persuaded India to jump out of the deal, leaving Iran and Pakistan to implement the project. It is an undeniable fact that <strong>Pakistan has no cheaper and safer option</strong> than getting the Iranian gas. The laying of the pipeline on our side of the border must be taken up immediately, since <strong>Iran has already constructed their part of the pipeline up to Pakistani border</strong>. Any effort to undo this vital project would be a criminal act against national interests.</p>

<p>Catch that? While the American-backed pipeline might be done in two years' time, the Iranian-backed pipeline is already built up to the border with Pakistan, just waiting for the hookup.</p>

<p> Happy New Year!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another e-Bay Arms Trader Busted]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/12/13/another-ebay-arms-trader-busted/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-13T23:27:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/12/13/another-ebay-arms-trader-busted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/12/geoff-roose-oregon-national-guard-150x115.jpg" alt="" />I just posted on this over at <a href="http://wweek.com/portland/blog-27977-corvallis-man-in-ebay-arms-case-was-three-tour-army-veteran.html">Willamette Week</a>. Geoffrey B. Roose, a self-described three-tour U.S. Army veteran from Oregon, was arrested last week following a sting by Homeland Security agents who stumbled across his eBay store, where he was selling restricted (and apparently stolen) Trijicon military rifle scopes.</p>

<p>Roose&rsquo;s eBay username: &ldquo;mr.f.u.up.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Investigators got a hold of Roose&rsquo;s emails. In one, he reacted defensively to a prospective customer on eBay who pointed out that he appeared to be dealing in stolen government property.</p>

<p>&ldquo;You know what man,&rdquo; Roose began,</p>

<blockquote><p>I spent three tours overseas and it isn&rsquo;t my responsibility to police the world. … Take a load off and try worrying about your life, not stupid federal ITAR rules or stolen property. There is more government property wasted in a dumpster overseas then [sic] you will ever see on ebay. Sorry to be rude, but it&rsquo;s the god honest truth. … Check feedback before you accuse someone of potentially having stolen property. Deal with it, it happens. It&rsquo;s your tax dollars.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Federal Prosecutors Bust Defense Official For Taking Bribes]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/11/02/federal-prosecutors-bust-defense-official-for-taking-bribes/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-02T21:44:36+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/11/02/federal-prosecutors-bust-defense-official-for-taking-bribes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-18160-war_bribes.html"><img src="/images/2011/11/warbribes-123x150.jpg" alt="" /></a> I have a new cover story over at <em>Willamette Week</em> about a corruption case involving a former civilian official at the U.S. Army Special Operations Command now sitting in federal prison on 35 counts of bribery, extortion and receiving illegal gratuities. <a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-18160-war_bribes.html">Read it there</a>.</p>

<p>And keep checking back for updates—I expect WIB to resume a more regular posting schedule by the end of the year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Reminder That The Post-9/11 Decade Wasn't Bad For Everybody]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/09/07/a-reminder-that-the-post-911-decade-wasnt-bad-for-everybody/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T19:18:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/09/07/a-reminder-that-the-post-911-decade-wasnt-bad-for-everybody</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2011/09/FLIR-Huey-150x109.jpg" alt="" /> This week, I&rsquo;ve written a story about a large-but-low-profile Pentagon contractor for Willamette Week, the <a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-4276-eyes_on_the_prize.html">award-winning</a> paper in Portland, Oregon, where I&rsquo;ve been working since June. <a href="http://www.wweek.com/portland/article-17938-light_during_wartime.html">Read the story there</a>.</p>

<p>The contractor, <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/profiles/flir-systems/">FLIR Systems</a>, has claimed more Department of Defense and Homeland Security contracts than any other in the state, which has relatively few big contracts. It makes advanced imaging technology coveted by armed forces around the world.</p>

<blockquote><p>Since 9/11, its revenues have increased sixfold, to $1.4 billion last year. As impressive as that may be, consider FLIR’s profitability: from a $29 million loss in 2000 to a $56 million profit last year.</p></blockquote>

<p>Chairman and CEO Earl Ray Lewis III this year signed a contract that sets his base salary at $875,000 next year, several times what he made when he joined the company before 9/11. Forbes magazine says Lewis’ compensation last year totaled $5.4 million.</p>

<p>Late last month, blaming uncertainty around the military budget, FLIR announced it would lay off 40 workers in Wilsonville—one-tenth of its workforce in the state. Then last week, FLIR won a three-year, $52 million U.S. Navy contract for the Star SAFIRE thermal-imaging systems it manufactures in Wilsonville.</p>

<p>Recently the company struck deals with Pakistan and Saudi Arabia, two nominal US allies with spotted human rights records.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
