<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bullet Points | War Is Business]]></title>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/categories/bullet-points/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-31T21:25:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Corey Pein]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arming The Libyan Rebels: What To Do?]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/04/01/arm-libyan-rebels-just-do-it/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-01T17:27:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/04/01/arm-libyan-rebels-just-do-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/04/libya-rebel-just-do-it-nike.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/04/libya-rebel-just-do-it-nike.jpg" alt="" /></a>
Wouldn&rsquo;t it be nice if the Nike solution applied to everything? If the problem of whether (and how) the outside world should support the anti-Gadhafi forces in Libya were so simple, Obama could just appoint Phil Knight to be the next Secretary of State.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it&rsquo;s not so simple. When it comes to arming the Libyan rebels, many of the people saying &ldquo;just do it&rdquo; are the same people who were gung-ho about the last couple of American wars. It&rsquo;s not entirely fair to say that the mainstream journalists and overpaid think-tankers who supported the Iraq invasion early on ought to be banned from advising anyone about anything—but, well, they probably ought to be.</p>

<p>As painful as it is to give any number of discredited warmongers a fair hearing, it would be a bigger mistake to treat the horrific situation in Libya as a chance to reenact an eight-year-old domestic political dispute. Any seemingly reflexive stance on the matter—whether in favor of military action or against it—cannot, by definition, be based on an honest evaluation of the unique circumstances in Libya.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m always at pains to note that W.I.B. is not an antiwar website—it&rsquo;s an anti-war profiteering website. With that said, to my mind, the anti-intervention camp has produced the most persuasive arguments so far on Libya. There is absolutely no guarantee those arguments will persuade the right people. Indeed, at this point, it appears that Western leaders have already decided in favor of steadily increasing military involvement. Obama has already bypassed Congress to wage a bombing campaign (euphemistically known as the &ldquo;no-fly zone&rdquo;); absent domestic opposition, he is free to escalate as long as the uniformed military can bear the strain.</p>

<p>Keep reading for a brief roundup of the latest takes on the most crucial foreign policy question of 2011 (so far).</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>POINT IS MOOT</h3>

<blockquote><p>Forces loyal to Libya&rsquo;s leader of nearly 42 years spent much of this week pushing the rebels back about 100 miles along the coast, and the opposition was trying to regroup. The rebels had mortars Friday, weapons they previously appeared to have lacked, and on Thursday night they drove in a convoy with at least eight rocket launchers — more artillery than usual.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2011/04/01/501364/main20049578.shtml">This report</a> raises a question it doesn&rsquo;t answer: Where&rsquo;d those new weapons come from? Here&rsquo;s one possibility:</p>

<blockquote><p>The CIA personnel were sent in to contact opponents of Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi and assess their capabilities, two U.S. officials said.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;They&rsquo;re trying to sort out who could be turned into a military unit and who couldn&rsquo;t,&rdquo; said Bob Baer, a former CIA case officer…</p>

<p>U.S. officials familiar with Obama&rsquo;s covert action order said while it authorizes a potentially sweeping range of measures to support Libyan rebels, each specific operation &mdash; for example, sending in U.S. trainers, money or weapons &mdash; would require further &ldquo;permissions&rdquo; from the White House.</p>

<p>… <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/31/world/africa/31intel.html">The New York Times reported</a> that &ldquo;dozens&rdquo; of British special forces soldiers and officers from Britain&rsquo;s foreign intelligence agency, known as MI-6, are working inside Libya.</p>

<p>••• American and British intelligence agents are <a href="http://www.reuters.com/assets/print?aid=USTRE72U7NM20110331">already in Libya</a>. Reading between the lines of <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/04/01/world/africa/01military.html">multiple</a> <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1371056/Libya-David-Cameron-ready-arm-rebels-air-strikes-continue-Gaddafi-goes.html">international</a> <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/africaandindianocean/libya/8419575/Libya-Nato-insists-Alliance-will-enforce-arms-embargo.html">news</a> <a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/news/world/call-for-others-to-aid-libyas-ragtag-rebels/story-e6frg6so-1226032280100">accounts</a>, it seems that Yanks are limiting themselves to supplying &ldquo;training&rdquo; and intelligence to the rebel forces, while leaving the Brits (or other allied nations) to hand out hardware. This is pure speculation, but it jibes with the equivocal public statements of US and UK leaders.</p>

<h3>IN THIS CORNER—RAH RAH!</h3>

<blockquote><p>There are those who would caution that the United States does not know enough about the Libyan opposition to support it, but this is not entirely true. Some of the opposition leaders are former cabinet ministers and generals in the Libyan government, known to the United States and its allies. …</p></blockquote>

<p>The U.S. decision to support victims of aggression paid off in Bosnia and advanced America&rsquo;s interests and values. Involvement on the side of the democracy movement in Libya would enable the United States to exercise a positive influence on Libya&rsquo;s evolution and prevent destabilizing outcomes.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.rand.org/commentary/2011/03/24/CNN.html">This pro-war argument comes</a> from an upstanding Quiet American at the RAND Corporation, the most prestigious think-tank of the US military-industrial complex.</p>

<blockquote><p>Paul Wolfowitz, a deputy secretary of defense under former President George W. Bush, said it&rsquo;s vital the U.S. supports arming the rebels.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;I think we should be doing everything we can to support the opposition,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s true, we don&rsquo;t know what the opposition would be like when they take over, but there are actually some promising signs.&rdquo;</p>

<p>••• The architect of the Iraq invasion thinks getting deeply involved in an Arab civil war is a <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2011/POLITICS/03/31/arming.libya.rebels.analysts/">fantastic idea</a>.</p>

<h3>IN THIS CORNER—NAH…</h3>

<blockquote><p>Under what doctrine or posture might the Administration prosecute Viktor Bout on the one hand and, on the other, provide weaponry to ragtag Libyan rebels whose principles, capacity, training, discipline, and understanding of international human-rights norms seem so doubtful—and may prove to be no better than those of many of Bout’s alleged African clients?</p></blockquote>

<p>… There is no way to police the rebels’ conduct or to hold them accountable for their actions on the battlefield. It is not clear what the rebels are fighting for, other than survival and the possible opportunity to take power in a country loaded with oil.</p>

<p>••• Party-pooper <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2011/03/libya-dont-arm-the-rebels.html">Steve Coll</a> thinks he&rsquo;s so smart, with his facts and logic, and is just oh-so-superior the way he brings up morality and all that. Harrumph.</p>

<blockquote><p>NATO secretary-general Anders Fogh Rasmussen has ruled out arming Libyan rebels now that the organisation has assumed command of international military operations in the country.</p></blockquote>

<p>Speaking to reporters, Rasmussen said: &ldquo;We are there to protect the Libyan people, not to arm the people.&rdquo;</p>

<p>••• All <a href="http://www.defencemanagement.com/news_story.asp?id=15950">this statement</a> means, from what I can tell, is that a coup in Libya supported by key NATO members wouldn&rsquo;t officially be a NATO operation.</p>

<blockquote><p>Turkish Prime Minister Tayyip Erdogan said on Thursday he did not support the idea of arming Libyan rebels fighting to oust Muammar Gaddafi from power.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;Doing that would create a different situation in Libya and we do not find it appropriate to do that,&rdquo; Erdogan told reporters at a joint press conference with British Prime Minister David Cameron in London.</p>

<p>••• This must rank amont the least-articulate antiwar arguments expressed by a head of state in the last several decades years. <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2011/03/31/us-libya-britain-turkey-idUSTRE72U4CJ20110331">But there it is</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Global domestic policy probably shouldn’t include handing out guns to lots of unknown forces, even if we may be heartbroken that the Libyan people can’t fight back as effectively as they might otherwise. If we supply them with weapons, the fight may start to look more like ours than theirs, and that may backfire down the road. But the coalition should surely provide intelligence, logistical, and political support, and hope that the neighbors can find a way to clean up the neighborhood as best they can.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• John Torpey, a guest-poster on Juan Cole&rsquo;s blog, seems to <a href="http://www.juancole.com/2011/03/torpey-support-the-libyans-but-dont-arm-them.html">cautiously support</a> the current official US policy of providing &ldquo;training&rdquo; to the rebels, but like many liberals is wary of handing out weapons. From a military point of view, this seems ill-considered. What will those hands-off American advisers do when their rebel allies start losing because they&rsquo;re outgunned? That outcome seems likely, given reports like this one:</p>

<h3>WALK THE LINE…</h3>

<blockquote><p>With all the talk of arming Libyan rebels for their campaign against Colonel Muammar el-Qaddafi, it might be worthwhile to look at what the rebels are actually carrying and using in the field. …</p></blockquote>

<p>Have look at the picture [<a href="http://cjchivers.com/post/4243593612/can-you-i-d-this-libyan-rebel-weapon">here</a>]. The butt stock of that weapon belongs to a Degtyaryov DP machine gun, another of the Soviet Union’s successful and long-lasting infantry arms. The DP lies three generations back in Eastern bloc machine gunnery… </p>

<p>There is simply no telling how long such weapons will last. And this one…fires one of the most common types of combat ammunition on earth, the 7.62x54R — which means that it could remain well-supplied with ammunition for decades.</p>

<p>••• CJ Chivers <a href="http://cjchivers.com/post/4243593612/can-you-i-d-this-libyan-rebel-weapon">muddies the debate</a> with pesky details.</p>

<p>The picture at the top of this post came to me via <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/War-Is-Business/111598495562127">Facebook</a>. Does anyone know the original source? I&rsquo;m curious whether everything I&rsquo;m reading in to the image (support for the Libyan rebels) was intended by its creator.</p>

<p>Is this culture-jamming as propaganda? Or vice versa?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Race Begins To Keep Libyan Rebels Armed]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/08/race-begins-to-keep-libyan-rebels-armed/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-08T13:01:49+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/03/08/race-begins-to-keep-libyan-rebels-armed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/03/buck-mckeon-in-afghanistan.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/03/buck-mckeon-in-afghanistan-150x112.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h3>AFGHANISTAN</h3>

<blockquote><p>“I recently went on a fact finding mission in Afghanistan with other members of Congress as part of my new role as Chairman of House Armed Services. <a href="http://twitpic.com/4169h2">This picture</a> was taken on that trip with some of the wonderful children of Afghanistan."</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Buck McKeon traveled all that way for a photo-op, then ruined it by blinking just as his aide hit the camera shutter.</p>

<blockquote><p>USAID has given $39 million for the reconstruction of schools in Swat but <a href="http://pamirpost.newsvine.mobi/_news/2011/03/04/6190548-reviving-swat-stitch-by-stitch">due to bureaucratic hurdles</a> the transfer of money from centre to the province has been delayed.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Read: &ldquo;due to corruption.&rdquo; Maybe this calls for a fact-finding mission?</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Third-country nationals, originating from places such as Latin America, Africa, and Asia, compose 40% of the overall DoD contractor workforce in CENTCOM AOR, totaling over 70,000 people. There is no exact number as to how many third country nationals have served as contractors worldwide…</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Status check on America&rsquo;s <a href="http://web.peaceops.com/archives/1239">outsourced wars</a>.</p>

<h3>LIBYA</h3>

<blockquote><p>Food shortages in eastern Libya, the largest rebel-controlled area, have reached dire levels. Fighting has left food stocks depleted and food supply chains in shambles. Around Benghazi, food prices have reportedly risen by 50 to 75 percent.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• What a relief, then, that <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2011/03/how-food-could-determine-libyas-future/72097/">&ldquo;aid&rdquo; is on the way</a></p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;<a href="http://www.dailytelegraph.com.au/news/breaking-news/us-under-pressure-to-arm-libya-rebels/story-e6freuyi-1226017235934">I assume</a> that a lot of weapons are going to find their way there (to rebels in Libya) from <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/mar/06/sas-diplomatic-mission-in-libya">one means or another over</a> the course of the next weeks,&rdquo; Senate Foreign Relations Committee Chairman John Kerry, from Obama&rsquo;s Democratic Party, told CBS&rsquo;s Face the Nation on Sunday.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/middle-east/americas-secret-plan-to-arm-libyas-rebels-2234227.html">One means</a>…</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.ethicalcargo.org/en/newsroom/libya-suspect-flights">TRAFFICKING ALERT <strong><em> Suspect arms flights to Côte d'Ivoire and Libya </em></strong></a></p></blockquote>

<p>••• Or another.</p>

<blockquote><p>A United Nations Security Council arms embargo imposed on Libya on Friday could cost global defence manufacturers billions of dollars…</p></blockquote>

<p>••• The real victims in this tragedy are, of course, <a href="http://www.defpro.com/news/details/22419/">Russian arms manufacturers</a>…</p>

<blockquote><p>“There seems to be this idea that if people are supporting Qaddafi, it must be mercenaries from sub-Saharan Africa, because it could not be the work of Libyans,&ldquo; says Mr. Souare. "It must be these savage Africans.”</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Rumors of sub-Saharan mercs in Libya part of a <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/World/Africa/2011/0306/How-Qaddafi-helped-fuel-fury-toward-Africans-in-Libya">divide-and-conquer strategy</a>?</p>

<blockquote><p>The New Republic published an article sympathetic to Qaddafi that had been written by a prominent American intellectual paid by a firm that was being compensated by Libya to burnish the dictator&rsquo;s image.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• What? <a href="http://motherjones.com/politics/2011/03/libya-qaddafi-monitor-group?page=1">It&rsquo;s a free market</a>.</p>

<h3>UK</h3>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;On the issue of trade and on defence: We have some of the toughest controls anywhere in the world for selling [weapons abroad]… I don&rsquo;t think that trade is wrong in every circumstance. How can we expect a small country to manufacture and make all the things it needs to defend itself?&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• David Cameron defends the timing of his Middle Eastern arms sales tour to an <a href="http://english.aljazeera.net/">Al Jazeera English</a> interviewer on February 25.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2011/feb/18/envoy-saudi-bae-systems">BAE Systems hires Britain&rsquo;s former envoy to Saudi Arabia</a>: Sir Sherard Cowper-Coles played a key role in ending the Serious Fraud Office&rsquo;s investigation into BAE&rsquo;s al-Yamamah arms deal</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Total coincidence. He just answered the ad in the paper.</p>

<h3>RUSSIA</h3>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;For the very same money, Russia buys 14 tanks a year, and India 100.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• A Russian military prosecutor <a href="http://russiandefpolicy.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/corruption-and-the-gpv/">estimates</a> that between 45 and 50 percent of the money budgeted for arms procurement &ldquo;simply ended up in someone’s pocket.&rdquo;</p>

<h3>USA</h3>

<blockquote><p>The Pentagon’s premiere research arm, Darpa, awarded a substantial contract to a company co-founded by the agency’s director and currently run by her father.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• You call it a <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2011/03/darpa-gave-400000-to-chiefs-family-firm/?utm_source=co2hog">&ldquo;conflicts of interest&rdquo;</a>. I call it &ldquo;good business.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>“We constantly hear statements,” Kharoba began, “that Islam is a religion of peace, and we constantly hear of jihadists who are trying to kill as many non-Muslims as they can.” Kharoba’s course would establish for his students that one of these narratives speaks to a deep truth about Islam, and the other is a calculated lie…</p></blockquote>

<p>Kharoba belongs to a growing profession, one that is ballooning on the spigot of federal and state dollars set aside for counterterrorism efforts since the attacks of September 11, 2001. He is a counterterrorism instructor to America’s beat cops, one of several hundred working the law enforcement training circuit. Some are employed by large security contractors; others, like Kharoba, are independent operators.</p>

<p>••• Read about the massive, costly, state-sponsored program of <a href="http://www.washingtonmonthly.com/features/2011/1103.stalcup-craze.html">Islamophobic indoctrination</a> for local security officers throughout the US.</p>

<blockquote><p>The software he patented — which he claimed, among other things, could find terrorist plots hidden in broadcasts of the Arab network Al Jazeera; identify terrorists from Predator drone videos; and detect noise from hostile submarines — prompted an international false alarm that led President George W. Bush to order airliners to turn around over the Atlantic Ocean in 2003.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• What happens when misplaced faith in the miracles of technology combines with an unlimited expense account? <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/20/us/politics/20data.html">Things like this</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;We don&rsquo;t tell the whole story&rdquo; in our ads, says Randy Belote, a Northrop Grumman spokesman. &ldquo;We let the reader try to determine what&rsquo;s going on.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>Ordinary citizens who are baffled by Washington&rsquo;s ads can take comfort in the fact that people targeted by these ads sometimes don&rsquo;t understand them, either.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704637704576082212342743824.html">Also this</a>: Behind the mysterious ads on the DC Metro.</p>

<blockquote><p>Argentina seized the contents of a U.S. Air Force plane that was delivering equipment for a U.S.-led police-training course. Buenos Aires is claiming that the equipment was undeclared and thus subject to confiscation. &ldquo;<a href="http://www.hudson.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=publication_details&amp;id=7723">The United States must understand</a> that they can&rsquo;t send war materials without informing the government,&rdquo; [Argentine foreign minister Héctor Timerman] told CNN.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Well, Argentina must understand that <a href="http://newsimg.bbc.co.uk/media/images/41798000/jpg/_41798970_usa416.jpg">THESE COLORS DON&rsquo;T ASK PERMISSION!</a></p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.minyanville.com/businessmarkets/articles/defense-stocks-defense-spending-offbeat-news/2/11/2011/id/32767">Who knew that the company behind the salad shooter makes roughly double its income from household products on Pentagon contracts and generic Depends?</a></p></blockquote>

<p>••• &ldquo;Badass,&rdquo; or disquieting? Depends on your outlook.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Most of the big defense companies have been anticipating a downturn in military demand since at least the last decade,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;They&rsquo;re surprised that the downturn did not materialize when President Obama took office, and now they&rsquo;re beginning to suspect there won&rsquo;t be a downturn at all.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2011/02/04/AR2011020406136.html">Signed, sealed, delivered.</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Beginning in 1982, The Knights of Malta began an intensely collaborative partnership with the international aid organization AmeriCares—a charity group unique in its selective disaster relief to countries friendly to both U.S. business investment and foreign policy objectives. Literally billing itself as “The humanitarian arm of corporate America,” AmeriCares was founded and headed until 2002 by Robert Macauley: a college roommate of George H. W. Bush, a paper mill millionaire and a self-described (then self-denied) agent in the CIA’s WWII-era precursor, the OSS. Macauley was also the first non-Catholic to receive the coveted Cross of the Commander of the Order of Malta.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• A <a href="http://whowhatwhy.com/2011/02/23/pulitzer-prize-winner-seymour-hersh-and-the-men-who-want-him-committed/">long reply</a> to Sy Hersh&rsquo;s <a href="http://blog.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2011/01/21/me_and_seymour_hersh">critics</a> by Russ Baker.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[$29 Million In Contracts For Firms That Plotted Against Wikileaks, Greenwald]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/15/29-million-in-contracts-for-firms-that-plotted-against-wikileaks-greenwald/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-15T14:30:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/15/29-million-in-contracts-for-firms-that-plotted-against-wikileaks-greenwald</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.redbubble.com/products/configure/6200770-sticker"><img src="/images/2011/02/zombie-reagan-150x144.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<blockquote><p>America&rsquo;s hottest export: Weapons</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/02/10/news/international/america_exports_weapons_full.fortune/">Where have you been, Fortune</a>?</p>

<blockquote><p>[W]hoever governs Egypt, and whatever their aims and preferences, they will have to co-exist with a military that will likely remain strong and a newly empowered public that’s at the core seeking liberty.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Whew! <a href="http://www.politico.com/news/stories/0211/49333.html">With Mubarak gone</a>, the US can continue to arm Egypt without too much embarrassment.</p>

<blockquote><p>My initial reaction to all of this was to scoff at its absurdity.… But after learning a lot more over the last couple of days, I now take this more seriously… For one thing, it turns out that the firms involved here are large, legitimate and serious, and do <a href="http://emptywheel.firedoglake.com/2011/02/10/palantir-tries-to-preserve-their-government-contracts/">substantial amounts of work</a> for both the U.S. Government and the nation&rsquo;s largest private corporations (as but one example, see this email from a Stanford computer science student about Palantir).</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Glenn Greenwald is admirably level-headed in his <a href="http://www.salon.com/news/opinion/glenn_greenwald/2011/02/11/campaigns/index.html">response</a> to the anti-Wikileaks presentation (<a href="http://wikileaks.ch/IMG/pdf/WikiLeaks_Response_v6.pdf">pdf</a>) prepared by three government contractors, <a href="http://usaspending.gov/search?query=&amp;searchtype=&amp;formFields=eyJSZWNpcGllbnROYW1lTGNhc2UiOlsiSGJnYXJ5ICBJbmMuIl19#">HBGary</a>, <a href="http://usaspending.gov/search?query=&amp;searchtype=&amp;formFields=eyJTZWFyY2hUZXJtIjpbInBhbGFudGlyIl19#">Palantir</a> and <a href="http://usaspending.gov/search?query=&amp;searchtype=&amp;formFields=eyJTZWFyY2hUZXJtIjpbImJlcmljbyJdfQ==#">Berico Technologies</a>. The presentation named Greenwald as an example of the type of public figure whose support is necessary to Wikileaks' survival.</p>

<blockquote><p>Kilcoyne said the police officers were not having the “occasional puff” – there were occasions when they “couldn’t walk straight … These are people with weapons.”</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Afghan cops are <a href="http://publicintelligence.net/afghan-police-drug-culture-leads-to-constant-highness/?utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">constantly stoned</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Drug cartels increased the number of clandestine airstrips to receive aircraft from Central and South America and created narco-hubs  in the country, despite the efforts of the government of Mexico to control its airspace.…</p></blockquote>

<p>Between 2006 and 2010 at least 469 aircraft were seized. Most are single-engine Cessna aircraft, capable of carrying up to 250 kilograms of cargo.</p>

<p>••• The Mexican FedEx <a href="http://www.milenio.com/node/640740">expands</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>The deal with China gives Beijing a lucrative entry into the Latin American arms market. Bolivia will pay at least $58 million &mdash; most of it covered by a Chinese government loan &mdash; for six K-8 Karakorum jets that are to be delivered by April.…</p></blockquote>

<p>The K-8 is a low-budget attack aircraft…initially built jointly by China Nanchang Aircraft Manufacturing Corporation and state-run Pakistan Aeronautical Complex. China&rsquo;s Hongdu Aviation Industry Corp. is the main contractor for the plane.</p>

<p>••• Meanwhile, the Bolivian anti-narco air force increases by <a href="http://dalje.com/en-economy/bolivia-buys-more-arms-to-fight-drug-traffickers/338780">six</a> planes.</p>

<blockquote><p>The number of military-owned vehicles that ran afoul of traffic rules on the roads of Beijing fell sharply…</p></blockquote>

<p>In 1997, the State Council mandated that those who drive military vehicles enjoy special treatment. In addition to the traffic rules, they do not have to pay parking fees.</p>

<p>••• Chinese military <a href="http://china.globaltimes.cn/society/2011-02/621234.html">fringe benefits</a> take a hit.</p>

<blockquote><p>Where, oh where, are China’s killer drones?</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2011/02/where-are-chinas-killer-drones/?utm_source=co2hog">Drones for everyone!</a></p>

<blockquote><p>The U.S. Air Force has bought another 24 MQ-9 Reaper UAVs, for about $6.2 million each. … So far, between the air force and CIA (a major operator of UAVs over Pakistan, and other places), about 20 percent of the 500 MQ-1 and MQ-9s built have been lost.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• American drones crash twice as often as <a href="http://www.strategypage.com/htmw/htairfo/articles/20110208.aspx">manned fighter jets</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>If we don’t like drones (and we shouldn’t), we must ask questions about what our helicopters and F-16s are doing in the north. If we don’t like targeted killings in Karachi, we should raise our voice against them in Balochistan too.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Mosharraf Zaidi, <a href="http://www.mosharrafzaidi.com/2011/02/09/drowning-in-our-delusions/">voice of reason</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Tetsuro is the last Japanese man still remaining in Kazakhstan out of the hundreds of thousands Stalin shipped to the most desolate parts of the Soviet Union, putting them to work in mines, in construction, and in factories. More than a tenth of them died due to the brutal working conditions.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.japansubculture.com/2011/02/the-last-japanese-man-remaining-in-kazakhstan-a-kafkian-tale-of-the-plight-of-a-japanese-pow-in-the-soviet-union/">Someone should make a movie</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>K2 was a key operations hub [for Afghanistan] until 2005, when the U.S. State Department objected to how the Uzbekistan government fired on protesters…killing several hundreds. Shortly thereafter, Uzbekistan kicked the U.S. out of K2.</p></blockquote>

<p>What has long been rumored, though, is that the U.S. was using some other bases, as well. And now we appear to have official confirmation of that, for the first time, from an unlikely source: Donald Rumsfeld, the U.S. secretary of defense during that period.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.eurasianet.org/node/62869">RummyLeaks</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Uh, Defender of the Constitution?&rdquo; Justin Bradfield of Maryland scoffed when I caught up with him after he walked out of Rumsfeld&rsquo;s speech. &ldquo;Let&rsquo;s see: he expanded the Defense Department more than pretty much any other defense secretary and he enforced the Patriot Act.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://tpmdc.talkingpointsmemo.com/2011/02/paul-supporters-hijack-cheney-rumsfeld-reunion.php">Tea Partiers</a> take a cue from Code Pink.</p>

<blockquote><p>The Pentagon…doesn&rsquo;t have a comprehensive count for the contractors it employs.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Maybe they should hire a consultant to <a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2011/02/09/pentagon-seeks-reduce-number-contractors-knowing/">figure it out</a>. If they haven&rsquo;t already.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The criminal complaint unsealed today details troubling allegations of public corruption impacting the integrity of the U.S. Department of Defense&rsquo;s contracting process,” said Special Agent-in-Charge Ed Bradley… “Unfortunately,…a Navy employee and a DoD contractor conspired to corrupt the DoD&rsquo;s procurement system and personally profit from their scheme.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Feds bust a $10 million kickback scheme involving &ldquo;work that was not performed…[on] modifications o[f] existing contracts&rdquo; (<a href="http://www.dodig.mil/IGInformation/IGInformationReleases/MarianoDutta-GuptaRelease2-8-2011.pdf">pdf</a>).</p>

<blockquote><p>I question the possibility of Russia and any NATO state going to war any time in the foreseeable future. But perhaps I am naive in this. If so, I would welcome those who disagree to comment with plausible scenarios that lead to military conflict between Russia and NATO–especially given the deplorable weakness of Russia’s conventional forces and the sad state of their conscripts.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://russiamil.wordpress.com/2011/02/08/russias-black-sea-threat/">Plausible scenarios</a>? What if Reagan returns from the grave?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All The News You Missed, From All Over]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/07/all-the-news-you-missed-from-all-over/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-07T14:22:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/02/07/all-the-news-you-missed-from-all-over</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/02/kabul-bank.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/02/kabul-bank-150x87.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<h3>AFGHANISTAN</h3>

<blockquote><p>“With Mahmoud at the bank,” the former official went on, “it was seen as an extension of the Karzai family.”</p></blockquote>

<p>••• According to its <a href="http://www.kabulbank.com/html/index.aspx">website</a>, Kabul Bank still offers &ldquo;deposit schemes.&rdquo; <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2011/02/14/110214fa_fact_filkins?currentPage=all">They&rsquo;re not kidding</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>To get America out of the war, Petraeus has turned to the network of warlords, drug runners and thieves known as the Afghan government, which the general himself has denounced as a &ldquo;criminal syndicate.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/king-davids-war-20110202?print=true">Another must-read by Michael Hastings</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Prosecutor Ian Dixey said the serviceman &ndash; who all worked as &lsquo;air movers&rsquo; loading and unloading military aircraft &ndash; exploited their position of trust to smuggle cigarettes into the UK from Afghanistan and Oman.</p></blockquote>

<p>The conspiracy was discovered when Customs officers searched a plane after it landed at RAF Lyneham and found 90,000 L&amp;M cigarettes from Kabul stashed in a cardboard box.</p>

<p>••• One of the British airmen in this smuggling ring kept &ldquo;<a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1353904/3-RAF-servicemen-jailed-smuggling-7m-cigarettes-Middle-East-military-flights.html#ixzz1DGywOSP6">a spreadsheet explaining the scam on his laptop</a>.&rdquo;</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Muhammad Alnabi, it showed, had paid the Taliban 1,600 afghanis, or about $37. Sergeant Akbar had paid 700 afghanis, and Abdulla Kaka had remitted 6,500, funds for a so-called shadow government to carry on its fight.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/02/07/world/asia/07taliban.html?_r=1&amp;partner=rss&amp;emc=rss&amp;pagewanted=all">Taxes in Taliban territory</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>According to an April 2010 report by the International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), the NATO-led security mission in Afghanistan, two federal contractors, Stallion Construction and Engineering and DynCorp International, violated security procedures at Kandahar Airfield by escorting undocumented foreign laborers onto the base.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Even in a country where the average worker&rsquo;s income is <a href="http://www.atimes.com/atimes/South_Asia/LA29Df04.html">$426 a year</a>, contractors find it <a href="http://pogoblog.typepad.com/pogo/2011/02/smuggled-contract-laborers-in-afghanistan-the-tip-of-the-iceberg.html">cheaper to hire illegal immigrants</a>.</p>

<h3>EGYPT</h3>

<blockquote><p>The American-made tear gas used to disperse pro-democracy protesters in Egypt earlier this week was sold to the country after government review, a State Department spokeswoman told us.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.propublica.org/blog/item/state-department-approved-export-of-u.s.-made-tear-gas-to-egyptian-govt">Honestly, we thought they were only going to use it on those Muslim Brother guys…</a></p>

<blockquote><p>France has suspended sales of arms and tear gas to Egypt.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/babylonbeyond/2011/02/egypt-france-suspends-arms-sales-.html">Obama can&rsquo;t do this because ____</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Germany suspends arms exports to Egypt</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.dw-world.de/dw/function/0,,83389_cid_14817837,00.html">&ldquo; _________</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>The widespread conflict in Egypt and the Middle East threatens to hold up deals on billions of dollars in arms sales that companies like Boeing and Lockheed Martin have been counting on to help offset defense cuts at home and in Europe.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.smartbrief.com/news/aia/storyDetails.jsp?issueid=0BEABA9C-A7CA-4092-8975-6A4905139B28&amp;copyid=80AD539D-85CD-4553-AF11-0735CAB9CB59&amp;campaign=twitter&amp;ref=twitter80AD539D-85CD-4553-AF11-0735CAB9CB59">Public opinion is so inconvenient sometimes</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>“Egypt’s youth. Beware rumors and listen to the voice of reason. Egypt is above all so preserve it.”</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.wired.com/dangerroom/2011/02/egypt-hacked-vodafone-to-send-pro-regime-texts/">This message brought to you by Vodafone</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The key problem with Wisner being sent to Cairo at the behest of Hillary,&rdquo; he says, &ldquo;is the conflict-of-interest aspect&hellip; More than this, the idea that the US is now subcontracting or &lsquo;privatising&rsquo; crisis management is another problem. Do the US lack diplomats?</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/americas/revealed-us-envoys-business-link-to-egypt-2206329.html">The special US envoy to Egypt is thoroughly conflicted</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>It remains unclear what role, if any, Mr. Ghonim played in organizing the Jan. 25 protest movement itself, the largest Egypt has seen in more than 30 years. However, he played a prominent role in online activism in the months ahead of the historic protests.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• A Google exec, <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703989504576127621712695188.html">now missing</a>, helped pave the way for Egypt&rsquo;s protests.</p>

<blockquote><p>[Egyptian generals] will also furnish a referendum on the decades-long U.S. policy of providing generous support to the Egyptian military precisely so it would play a moderating role within the country and serve as an insurance policy for American interests there. The United States has sent tens of billions of dollars to Egypt over the past 30 years, and the Pentagon brings more than 500 Egyptian officers to the United States every year for training at military war colleges. The Obama administration is about to find out whether those investments have paid off.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.nationaljournal.com/member/magazine/military-exercised-20110203">Mubarak isn&rsquo;t America&rsquo;s only ally in Egypt</a>.</p>

<h3>RUSSIA</h3>

<blockquote><p>Russia has ordered a search for a missing military satellite that apparently was put into the wrong orbit shortly after launch today.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.globalsecurity.org/space/library/news/2011/space-110201-rferl01.htm">Oopski</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Russia has been warning Tajikistan that the U.S. wants to overthrow President Emomali Rakhmon for the sake of eliminating Russian influence in the country and creating &ldquo;a string of anti-Russia military bases from Baghram to Manas.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.eurasianet.org/node/62836">Party like it&rsquo;s 1985!</a></p>

<h3>WASHINGTON</h3>

<blockquote><p>The US military paid 285 billion dollars over three years to hundreds of military contractors that defrauded the Pentagon over the same stretch of time, a US senator charged Wednesday.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5jcxhmm-8zY5onCcWZMNUyai6XGZw?docId=CNG.4aae4371b956b57599c1a3203f206025.401">What? They said sorry, didn&rsquo;t they?</a></p>

<blockquote><p>In March 2009 in Quantico, Virginia, five Marines were injured during a training exercise. Some had to be medevaced after a 40mm grenade exploded in the air just 15-20 meters from the muzzle of the grenade launcher. It was the second time that day a grenade exploded prematurely.</p></blockquote>

<p>The investigation blamed a defective fuze.… Out of the six lots of grenades used that day, DSE Inc. was the primary contractor of half of them.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.abcactionnews.com/dpp/news/local_news/investigations/Former-employee-alleges-military-contractor-is-selling-faulty-grenades-to-the-U.S.-Army">The consequences of war profiteering</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>In an about-face, the Army has suspended all of its ongoing insourcing activities, potentially savings thousands of private sector positions.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.govexec.com/dailyfed/0211/020311rb2.htm">Secretary Gates' plan to cut back on contracting isn&rsquo;t working</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>UAV designers and engineers for years have wondered if and when the Defense Department will be ready to embrace new concepts for deploying UAVs, such as in more autonomous roles, or as “swarms” of aircraft that “think” independently. … UAVs would communicate and share relevant information and, in response to changing threats, would redirect themselves.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.nationaldefensemagazine.org/blog/Lists/Posts/Post.aspx?ID=301">Sentient swarms of heavily armed flying robots—sounds like a great idea!</a></p>

<h3>ALL OVER</h3>

<blockquote><p>The Indian government is trying to give all 1.2 billion Indians something like an American Social Security number, but more secure. Because each “universal identity number” (UID) will be tied to biometric markers, it will prove beyond reasonable doubt that anyone who has one is who he says he is.…</p></blockquote>

<p>This mighty task has been awarded to private contractors in an unusual way. There are three vendors: Accenture and L-1 Identity Solutions of America, plus Morpho of France.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.economist.com/node/18010459">Western corporations are building the Indian surveillance state</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Cuba officials have said that Gross, a subcontractor for Bethesda-based Development Alternatives, was clearly violating their laws when he tried to provide Jewish groups online access via satellite connections.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2011/02/04/AR2011020406989.html?tid=nn_twitter">Trouble in worker&rsquo;s paradise</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>U.S. military agencies in September 2010 signed contracts for construction at Tolemaida, Larandia and Malaga bases in Colombia worth nearly US$5 million…</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://upsidedownworld.org/main/news-briefs-archives-68/2892-pentagon-building-bases-in-central-america-and-colombia">Drug war update I</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>A former federal agent was sentenced today to 120 months in prison for conspiring to steal 50 kilograms of cocaine from a purported drug dealer, with the intent to distribute the drugs…</p></blockquote>

<p>••• Drug war update II (<a href="http://www.dhs.gov/xoig/assets/press/oigpr_020211a.pdf">pdf</a>).</p>

<blockquote><p>British Muslims are travelling to Somalia for “jihadi tourism” to train for terrorist attacks in Britain, the secret documents reveal.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/wikileaks/8302186/WikiLeaks-cables-British-Muslims-travelling-to-Somalia-for-jihadi-tourism.html">Is hotel included?</a></p>

<blockquote><p>The international shipping industry is truly disturbed at reports that pirates have been torturing seafarers physically and mentally, often in the most barbaric ways, including hanging them over the ship’s side by ropes around their ankles with their heads under water and even subjecting them to the horrendous practice of keelhauling.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.logisticsmanager.com/Articles/Article.aspx?liArticleID=15486">Now you know what keelhauling is</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Much as a major argument for the privatization of companies is that private enterprises tend to generate greater proﬁts, so, too, in the world of terrorist groups can privatization mean an enhanced cash ﬂow.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/david-isenberg/privatization-its-not-jus_b_816970.html?ref=tw">Look forward to Al Qaeda&rsquo;s IPO</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[News Of The World Beyond Egypt]]></title>
    <link href="http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/01/31/beyond-egypt/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-31T11:03:12+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://coreyp.github.com/warisbusiness/blog/2011/01/31/beyond-egypt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/images/2011/01/MQ-8B_Fire_Scout-northrop.jpg"><img src="/images/2011/01/MQ-8B_Fire_Scout-northrop-150x112.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<blockquote><p>The funds to pay for new unmanned technologies are being reallocated from other programs within the Navy’s budget — part of the &ldquo;efficiencies&rdquo; drill mandated by Defense Secretary Robert Gates.</p></blockquote>

<p>Navy Undersecretary Robert Work said that the department is planning to add $800 million to the budget for the MQ-8B Fire Scout vertical take-off and landing unmanned aircraft program.</p>

<p>••• This is <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/news/rent-a-generals-and-the-militarization-of-the-economy/">the same Fire Scout</a> that the Navy decided to build after extensive lobbying by Northrop Grumman&rsquo;s Rent-A-Generals, then decided it didn&rsquo;t need. Now, the program is <a href="http://www.nationaldefensemagazine.org/blog/Lists/Posts/Post.aspx?ID=296">back to life</a> with money freed up by Pentagon &ldquo;cuts.&rdquo; Support the troops!</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;[S]upporting the troops” has become a categorical imperative across the political spectrum.  In theory, such support might find expression in a determination to protect those troops from abuse, and so translate into wariness about committing soldiers to unnecessary or unnecessarily costly wars. In practice, however, “supporting the troops” has found expression in an insistence upon providing the Pentagon with open-ended drawing rights on the nation’s treasury, thereby creating massive barriers to any proposal to affect more than symbolic reductions in military spending.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.tomdispatch.com/blog/175347/tomgram:_andrew_bacevich,_pentagon,_inc./">Support the Troops!</a>
<img src="/images/2011/01/jon-stewart.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote><p>There is a reverence for the military in the US…that transcends political affiliation and pervades popular culture. On aeroplanes the flight attendant will announce if there are soldiers on board to great applause. When I attended a recording of The Daily Show, John [sic] Stewart made a special point before the show of thanking the servicemen in the audience.</p></blockquote>

<p>But while the admiration for those who serve and die may be deep and widespread, interest in what they are doing and why they are doing it is shallow and fleeting.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2011/jan/30/afghanistan-us-troops-dying">Seriously: Support the troops! We really, really mean it</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>It may not be politically correct to suggest letting mercenaries deal with humanitarian nightmares like Somalia and Darfur. But political correctness doesn’t save lives. Sending in mercenaries would.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• On second thought, <a href="http://www.boston.com/bostonglobe/editorial_opinion/oped/articles/2011/01/30/the_case_for_mercenaries_in_somalia/">support the mercenaries</a>—it&rsquo;s a lot easier.</p>

<blockquote><p>A semiautonomous regional government in Somalia on Friday defied the central government&rsquo;s decision to end relations with a private security company linked to the founder of Blackwater Worldwide, underscoring the weakness of the authorities in Mogadishu.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/canadianpress/article/ALeqM5jhsei1Jvzuy9k1hAp4_Yw6PqrjIg?docId=5779860">Who&rsquo;s in charge here?</a> The AP follows up the story of Saracen International and Erik Prince in Somalia.</p>

<blockquote><p>Is our own Saracen International tied to a plot to tinker in international politics? Heck if we know.</p></blockquote>

<p>But we can tell you that Bill Lawrence, one of the company&rsquo;s principals, is an 83-year-old engineer who&rsquo;s not only interested in killer SUVs, but also wants to be a pioneer of accessories for hookahs.</p>

<p>••• Phoenix New Times <a href="http://blogs.phoenixnewtimes.com/valleyfever/2011/01/suv-with-pop-up-machine-gun.php">interviews</a> the Saracen (Arizona) owner first spotlighted <a href="http://www.warisbusiness.com/features/deal-of-the-month/saracen-international-somalia/">here</a> and teases out the details that, &ldquo;Roger Harrison, his business partner was a former ambassador to Jordan.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The more weapons the governments in Khartoum and Juba acquire, the more we will see arms ‘seeping’ from their armed forces to proxies and non-state armed actors, via theft, sales, corruption, battle-field losses, and so forth,&rdquo; she explains.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• I&rsquo;m quoted in this <a href="http://www.ipsnews.net/news.asp?idnews=54286">IPS story</a> by Hilaire Avril on what a global small arms treaty could mean for sub-Saharan Africa.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;This affair concerns individuals who were involved in a wider network of arms deals that could have seen tens of thousands of weapons flooding into Iraq with seemingly no controls or accountability,&rdquo; Sprague said.</p></blockquote>

<p>••• A baby-faced British arms dealer is <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/jan/30/ak47-arms-conspiracy-china-united-states">wanted by US prosecutors</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>More than 62,000 firearms have disappeared from the inventories of licensed U.S. gun dealers in the past three years</p></blockquote>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2011/01/25/AR2011012500867.html">Mere spoilage</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>As part of the Afghan tradition of bacha bazi, literally “boy play,” boys as young as 9 are dressed as girls and trained to dance for male audiences, then prostituted in an auction to the highest bidder. Many powerful men, particularly commanders in the military and the police, keep such boys, often dressed in uniforms, as constant companions for sexual purposes.</p></blockquote>

<p>… The Taliban originally came to prominence in Kandahar when they intervened in a fight between two pedophile warlords over the possession of a coveted dancing boy. The Taliban also oppose the practice, and banned it when they were in power.</p>

<p>••• <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/01/30/world/asia/30afghan.html">Something worth thinking about</a>: The Taliban banned pederasty, but not the American proxy force.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
